elderly.com 2018-12-14

# Privacy Policy | Elderly Instruments

Elderly Instruments respects the privacy of our customers. This Privacy Policy describes what information we collect from our customers, and how we use and store it. This includes information provided when you place an order online at www.elderly.com; via phone, mail or fax; or in our showroom in Lansing, MI. It also includes information that you provide when you create a customer account on our website, as well as additional communications via web forms, email, phone, letter, or in person. 

As described below, we share some information with the trusted third-parties who assist us in our core business activities, such as processing your orders and payments, and maintaining and enhancing our website. With your consent, we may also share some information with companies that send promotional emails on our behalf. Except for these partners who directly support our own business activities, we do NOT sell, trade, or otherwise share your personal information with other businesses or organizations. 

## Information We Collect (and when we collect it)

#### Information that you provide:

When you place an order or set up an online account, you provide personal contact information which may include your full name, email address, phone number(s), billing address(es) and shipping address(es). You may also provide payment information, such as credit card information. If you purchase a gift, or a gift certificate, you may provide the recipient's name, shipping address, phone number, and/or email address. 

Similarly, you may provide personal contact information when you communicate with us for other reasons, such as: selling a used instrument to us (or consigning one through us), signing up for email newsletters, or entering a drawing or contest. 

You may also choose to share other information about your interests or preferences, via web forms, live online chat, phone calls, emails, letters, or in person. We may store some of this information, to process your orders, notify you about product availability, and otherwise provide you with the best possible customer service. 

You may voluntarily submit information to publicly-available portions of our site, such as product reviews. We reserve the right to remove any material that we believe to be offensive, libelous, or in violation of copyright laws. 

#### Information that we receive automatically:

When you place an order online, we may collect technical information including (but not limited to) the type of device, its IP (Internet Protocol) address, its geographic location, and the type and version of your browser and operating system. We may also collect and store usage data when you visit our website, including the site from which you linked to it, which of our webpages you view, and how long you look at them. 

## How We Use and Store the Data

In general, our primary use of any personal information is to process customers' orders. As related activities, we use personal information to communicate with our customers, and to offer them the best possible service. We also use some data to support our legitimate business interest in maintaining and improving our website. 

When you voluntarily create an online account, our website stores your contact data for your own convenience, so you don't have to re-enter it every time you place a new order. 

When you place an order (online; via phone, email, or fax; or in our showroom), we use your personal data to process that order and to contact you about it as necessary. We retain that personal data, and the details of your order, for several reasons: to assist in processing refunds and returns; to respond to your questions about the order or the merchandise; to resolve disputes or customer service issues; to allow us to provide you with your past sales history; and to allow us to customize promotional emails, ads, or other communications to reflect your specific interests based on your past purchases. 

We may store the last four digits of the credit card number that was used on an order. But, for your security, Elderly Instruments does NOT store your complete credit card information on our website or our internal computer systems. 

We use several trusted and established third-party service providers to help us process orders. They include credit card processors, other payment services like PayPal and Affirm, and shippers like FedEx, USPS and UPS. Sharing data with these partners is necessary for us to perform our core business activities -- processing orders, payments, returns, and refunds -- and they are prohibited from using your information except for the purposes that we specify, or as required by law. 

We use the services of a trusted service provider in order to help us prevent online fraud. Our service provider may use and process your personal information in accordance with applicable privacy and data protection laws. You can read about the ways by which our service provider may use and process your personal information at this address: [www.forter.com/forter-privacy-policy](https://www.forter.com/forter-privacy-policy/)

Under specific and necessary circumstances, we may share some of your information with a manufacturer or supplier. The most common situations are to process a "drop-ship" order (when the supplier ships the merchandise directly to you), or when required to validate a manufacturer's warranty. 

We care about the security of your personal data. We follow industry standards to protect your data whenever you submit information to us, we share it with our trusted service providers, and we use and store it. When it's necessary for our service partners to store and use your data, they likewise follow industry standards for protecting it. We constantly monitor our systems and implement new safeguards as they become available. However, we acknowledge that no data transmissions can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. 

With your consent, if you provided your email address to us, we may use it to send you periodic promotional messages about new products, special offers, and other useful information. We may use your past order history to customize such messages and show you specific products that might interest you. See the "Opting Out" section below if you wish to withdraw your consent. 

Except for these companies that directly support our own business activities, we do NOT sell, trade, or otherwise share your personal information with other businesses or organizations. 

You may post reviews or other publicly-viewable information on elderly.com. Once it has been displayed, we cannot control its dissemination or future use by others. 

## Cookies

Like most e-commerce sites, elderly.com uses cookies. These are small files on your computer (or other access device) which store information about your activity on our website. Cookies allow us to provide you with an improved and customized online experience. 

Some cookies are only used during the time you're online, and they're deleted after you close your web browser. Other "persistent" cookies are stored on your device for a longer period; these can be convenient when (for example) they remember information that you entered into a web form on a prior occasion, so you don't have to retype it again. 

We also use cookies (and related files called pixels or web beacons) to log your usage of our site -- for example, what pages you visit and how long you look at each one. With the assistance of trusted third-party services like Google Analytics, we can analyze the combined usage data from many customers to evaluate how well our website is working, and to judge which pages and items seem to be most popular. We can also tailor promotional messages to your individual interests, based on your activity on our site. If you do not wish to receive such messages, see "Opting Out," below. 

With our cooperation, other websites may be able to read our cookies on your device, recognize that you have visited our website, and display a customized advertisement for Elderly Instruments on their own site; however, those other sites can't obtain any personal contact information from those cookies. 

Web browsers offer tools to control whether or not your device will accept cookies, and to delete any cookies that already exist there. You can usually find instructions by using the "Help" function of your web browser, or by consulting a website like [whatarecookies.com](http://www.whatarecookies.com/)

Please note that by deleting or disabling cookies, you may not be able to access certain areas or features of our site, including our shopping cart. 

## Social Media

If you post to Elderly Instruments' social media accounts (such as Facebook, Twitter, Tumblr, etc.), the content -- including images and videos -- is subject to the policies of those respective platforms. This applies whether or not you linked to those platforms directly from elderly.com. Please consult the Terms of Use and Privacy Policies of those social media platforms. 

## Other Third-Party Sites Linked from Our Website

Our website offers financing via Affirm. If you click on a link to apply for such a loan, you will be directed to fill out an application on their own website. The information that you enter on affirm.com is subject to their own Privacy Policy, available here: [www.affirm.com/privacy](https://www.affirm.com/privacy)

Our "Events" page may include links to websites belonging to certain artists, venues, festivals, or other organizations, or to ticket services like brownpapertickets.com. Any information that you directly provide to those third-party sites is subject to their own respective Privacy Policies and Terms of Use. 

## Opting Out

If you prefer not to receive our promotional emails, you can opt-out by clicking on the "Unsubscribe" link at the bottom of any of those messages. After a short time to process your request, we will block your address from receiving promotional emails, although we may still send you shipping confirmations or personal communications about your orders. 

We use Google Analytics to analyze our customers' usage of our site, without identifying them personally. You can learn more about this, and to opt out of being included in Google Analytics, at: [Google Analytics](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/)

## Reviewing / Correcting / Deleting Personal Data

If you have created an account on elderly.com, you can login and correct or replace your contact information yourself. 

You can also contact us to update your personal contact information (see "Contact Us," below). 

Under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), members of the EU have the right to see what personal information we have stored about them, to ask us to make corrections, or to have us delete their data from our computer systems. Note that if we delete all of your personal information, we may not be able to answer questions about your past orders or to accept returns of that merchandise. 

We will require verification of your identity before revealing, modifying, or deleting your personal data. 

## Children / Minors

We don't knowingly collect personal information from people under the age of 13, or residents of the EU under the age of 16, without explicit permission from a parent or guardian. If you believe that we have retained personal information from such a minor, without parental consent, please contact us and we'll take immediate steps to delete it. 

## Data Transfer

The personal information that we collect is stored and processed within the United States. If you use our website (or provide information by other means) from another country, you are consenting to the transfer of that information to the United States, whose laws relating to the storage and use of personal data may differ from your own. 

## Contact Us

If you have questions about this Policy, wish to examine your personal data that we have stored, or wish to request that we update or delete your information, please contact us in any of the following ways: 

  * Email us at [privacy@elderly.com](mailto:privacy@elderly.com)
  * Write to us at Elderly Instruments, Attention: Privacy Inquiry, 1100 N. Washington Avenue, Lansing, MI 48906 USA
  * Call us at 1-888-473-5810 (toll-free within the USA)

We will require verification of your identity before revealing, modifying, or deleting your personal data. 

## Changes to This Policy

We may occasionally make changes to this Policy. The current version will always be available on our website, including the date of the latest revision. 

Revised 7/30/18
